Elliot S. Wolk Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Elliot S. Wolk Papers.
1961-1985.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Wolk, Elliot S.,
2.5 linear feet.
Professor of Mathematics at the University of Connecticut until his retirement in 1988.
MSS19880002
Biography
Elliot S. Wolk was a professor of Mathematics at the University of Connecticut until his retirement in 1988.
Scope and Content
The papers in this collection document Wolk's membership on the Faculty Advisory Committee to the Board of Higher Education from 1977-1983. The papers include data on such subjects as the unionization of faculty and the reorganization plans for higher education in Connecticut.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administrative, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
American Federation of Teachers Nwesletter 1962-1976
Anticipating the 1980s: Report and Recommendation to the General Assembly on Higher Wducation in Connecticut. Board of Higher Education, 1979. Dodd Call No. C 5722
Federation of University Teachers Newsletter 1971-1975
Report of the Governor's Commission on Higher Education and the Economy 1982 Dodd Coll No. C 5625
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut—Faculty.; Connecticut. Board of Higher Education. Faculty Advisory Committee.
Subjects:
Collective bargaining—College teachers—United States.; College teachers' unions—United States.; College teachers Salaries, etc.—United States.; Universities and colleges—United States—Administration.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Press releases.; School Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Notes.
Occupations:
Professor.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Dr. Wolk in 1988.
Detailed Description
- Series I: American Federation of Teachers, 1961-1983
  - Babbidge, Homer D., 1962-1964 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Budgets, 1975-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Communication
    - Trustees, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Trustees, 1961-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - “Dear Colleague” letters, 1961-1963 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Jorgenson, Albert N., 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Jorgenson and Trustees, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Membership Lists, 1971-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1961-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Resolution to Senate, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Salary Bills, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Salary Study, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Statement to Faculty, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
- Series II: Federation of University Teachers, 1971-1976
  - American Federation of Teachers Position Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Federation of University Teachers, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Higher Education Program: Faculty Suit against State because of...salary increments, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Legal Suit against State of Connecticut, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Legislative Hearings, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Membership Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Position papers and correspondence, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Salaries, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - State Convocation for Higher Education, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Statement by Department Heads, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Structure of Higher Education: Statements, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - UConn: The Commission on University Governance, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - UConn: Study of Cost of Instruction and Faculty Performance and Accountability, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
- Series III: Collective Bargaining, 1972-1976
  - Collective Bargaining: The Drive for Faculty Collective Bargaining, 1972-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Collective Bargaining Agent Election, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - Collective Bargaining Campaign literature, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Collective Bargaining campaign literature: AFT and AAP, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 30-31)
  - Collective Bargaining campaign material, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Collective Bargaining for University faculty, 1973-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 33-34)
  - Collective Bargaining unit, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Collective Bargaining Act and related materials, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - Collective Bargaining Bill, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Elias “Warning Letters”, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - Election of Bargaining Agent, 1975-1976 (Box 2:, Folder 44-45)
  - Librarians Hearing, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - Post election material, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - Senate Statement, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - State Labor Board, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
- Series IV: Faculty Advisory Committee to Board of Higher Education, 1977-1985
  - Correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - Board of Governors, Standing Committee, Bill 620, 1983-1985 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
  - Analysis and Response: Majority and Minority Reports on the Governor's Commission on Higher Education and the Economy, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Draft to Legislature, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - Governor's Commission, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - Response to Commission, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - Reorganization
    - Bills on, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 54-55)
    - Degree “Productivity”, 1979-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - Draft Statement “Public Higher Education”, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
    - Enrollment Projections, 1979-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - Freedom of Information Hearing, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Faculty Response, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - Faculty Statement, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - Higher Education Bills, 1979, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Reorganization Proposal, 1979-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - Responses to Board of Higher Education, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 64)